<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mountains</title>
    <link>https://my_page.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Mountains</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://my_page.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title> Cho Oyu, Himalayas, Nepal/Tibet Autonomous Region, China – 8188m</title>
      <link>https://my_page.github.io/highest-mountains/info_5/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my_page.github.io/highest-mountains/info_5/</guid>
      <description>Cho Oyu, Himalayas, Nepal/Tibet Autonomous Region, China – 8188m At 8,188 meters (26,864 feet), Cho Oyu is the sixth-highest mountain in the world and is considered one of the easier 8,000-meter peaks to climb. Located in the Himalayas on the Nepal-Tibet border, Cho Oyu presents a slightly less daunting challenge for mountaineers compared to its neighboring peaks.&#xA;Duck additional info: Cho Oyu means &amp;quot; Turquoise Goddess&amp;quot; in Tibetan. [2] The mountain is the westernmost major peak of the Khumbu sub-section of the Mahalangur Himalaya 20 km west of Mount Everest.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Dhaulagiri, Nepal – 8167m</title>
      <link>https://my_page.github.io/highest-mountains/info_6/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my_page.github.io/highest-mountains/info_6/</guid>
      <description>Dhaulagiri, Nepal – 8167m Dhaulagiri, standing at 8,167 meters (26,795 feet), takes its name from the Sanskrit words “dhaula” meaning white and “giri” meaning mountain. Located in the Dhaulagiri mountain range in Nepal, this peak is known for its massive glaciers and deep valleys, making it a spectacular sight to behold.&#xA;Duck additional info: Dhaulagiri, located in Nepal, is the seventh highest mountain in the world at 8,167 metres (26,795 ft) above sea level, and the highest mountain within the borders of a single country.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> K2, Karakoram, Pakistan/China – 8611m</title>
      <link>https://my_page.github.io/highest-mountains/info_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my_page.github.io/highest-mountains/info_1/</guid>
      <description>K2, Karakoram, Pakistan/China – 8611m Located in the Karakoram mountain range on the China-Pakistan border, K2 stands at 8,611 meters (28,251 feet), making it the second-highest mountain in the world. Known as the “Savage Mountain,” K2 is considered one of the most difficult and dangerous mountains to climb. Its steep pitches, unpredictable weather, and avalanches make it a challenging and deadly climb. In fact, the fatality rate for those attempting to summit K2 is around 25%, making it even more treacherous than Everest.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Kangchenjunga, Himalayas, Nepal/India – 8586m</title>
      <link>https://my_page.github.io/highest-mountains/info_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my_page.github.io/highest-mountains/info_2/</guid>
      <description>Kangchenjunga, Himalayas, Nepal/India – 8586m Located on the border of Nepal and India, Kangchenjunga stands at 8,586 meters (28,169 feet), making it the third-highest mountain in the world. The name “Kangchenjunga” translates to “Five Treasures of Snow,” representing the five peaks that make up the mountain. In Nepali and Sikkimese culture, Kangchenjunga is considered sacred and is worshipped as a deity.&#xA;Duck additional info: Kangchenjunga, also spelled Kanchenjunga, Kanchanjanghā and Khangchendzonga, is the third-highest mountain in the world.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Lhotse, Himalayas, Nepal/Tibet Autonomous Region, China – 8516m</title>
      <link>https://my_page.github.io/highest-mountains/info_3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my_page.github.io/highest-mountains/info_3/</guid>
      <description>Lhotse, Himalayas, Nepal/Tibet Autonomous Region, China – 8516m Standing at 8,516 meters (27,940 feet), Lhotse is the fourth-highest mountain in the world and the closest neighbor to Mount Everest. In fact, Lhotse shares a section of its summit ridge with Everest, making it a popular destination for those attempting to summit both peaks in one expedition. Despite this, Lhotse still presents its own unique challenges and dangers.&#xA;Duck additional info: Kangshung Face as seen from orbit.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Makalu, Himalayas, Nepal/Tibet Autonomous Region, China – 8485m</title>
      <link>https://my_page.github.io/highest-mountains/info_4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my_page.github.io/highest-mountains/info_4/</guid>
      <description>Makalu, Himalayas, Nepal/Tibet Autonomous Region, China – 8485m The first successful summit of Lhotse was in 1956 by a Swiss team led by Ernst Reiss and Fritz Luchsinger. Since then, several routes have been established, each with its own challenges and risks. The South Face of Lhotse, in particular, is considered one of the steepest and most technical climbs in the world, with a nearly vertical slope of 3,131 meters (10,272 feet).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Manaslu, Nepal – 8163m</title>
      <link>https://my_page.github.io/highest-mountains/info_7/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my_page.github.io/highest-mountains/info_7/</guid>
      <description>Manaslu, Nepal – 8163m Located in the Mansiri Himalaya range of Nepal, Manaslu stands at 8,163 meters (26,781 feet). The name “Manaslu” translates to “Mountain of the Spirit,” and the mountain is considered sacred by the local Nepalese. Its beauty and formidable presence have made it a popular destination for climbers, although it is still considered a challenging and dangerous climb.&#xA;Duck additional info: Manaslu Circuit: My personal favorite 2-week trek through Tibetan villages and stunning scenery.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Mount Everest, Himalayas, Nepal/Tibet Autonomous Region, China – 8848m</title>
      <link>https://my_page.github.io/highest-mountains/info_0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my_page.github.io/highest-mountains/info_0/</guid>
      <description>Mount Everest, Himalayas, Nepal/Tibet Autonomous Region, China – 8848m At a staggering height of 8,848 meters (29,029 feet), Mount Everest stands as the tallest mountain in the world. Located in the Mahalangur Himalaya range of the Himalayas, on the border of Nepal and Tibet, Everest has long captured the fascination of climbers and adventurers alike. Sir Edmund Hillary and Tenzing Norgay were the first to successfully summit Mount Everest in 1953, and since then, thousands of brave souls have followed in their footsteps.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Nanga Parbat, Pakistan – 8126m</title>
      <link>https://my_page.github.io/highest-mountains/info_8/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my_page.github.io/highest-mountains/info_8/</guid>
      <description>Nanga Parbat, Pakistan – 8126m Nanga Parbat, standing at 8,126 meters (26,660 feet), is nicknamed the “Killer Mountain” due to its deadly and treacherous nature. Located in the Diamer district of Pakistan, Nanga Parbat has the distinction of being the only 8,000-meter peak located outside of the Himalayas. Its steep and snowy slopes, combined with unpredictable weather and high altitude, make it an extremely challenging climb.&#xA;Duck additional info: Nanga Parbat is not a single peak but consists of 20km long series of peaks and ridges culminating in an ice crest of (8126m).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>. Annapurna I, Nepal – 8091m</title>
      <link>https://my_page.github.io/highest-mountains/info_9/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://my_page.github.io/highest-mountains/info_9/</guid>
      <description>. Annapurna I, Nepal – 8091m Rounding out the list of the 10 highest mountains in the world is Annapurna I, standing at 8,091 meters (26,545 feet). Located in the Annapurna mountain range in Nepal, this peak was the first 8,000-meter mountain to be successfully summitted, back in 1950 by a French expedition led by Maurice Herzog.&#xA;Duck additional info: Annapurna (/ ˌ æ n ə ˈ p ʊər n ə ˌ-ˈ p ɜːr-/; Nepali: अन्नपूर्ण) is a mountain situated in the Annapurna mountain range of Gandaki Province, north-central Nepal.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
